Guide to the Yale Union Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Union records
1891-1927
RU 78
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The records consist of a constitution, tickets, agreements, a dinner menu, program records, correspondence and memorabilia documenting the Yale Union. Included is material concerning the 1892 debate against the Harvard Union.
Yale University. Yale Union
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of a constitution, tickets, agreements, a dinner menu, program records, correspondence and memorabilia documenting the Yale Union. Included is material concerning the 1892 debate against the Harvard Union.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Union, the first of three Yale student groups with a similar name, was founded in 1920 and disbanded in 1926.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Debates and debating; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Yale Union
- Yale Union records, Accession 1980-A-037
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence and memorabilia donated by John Lorance, Yale 1892, relating to the founding of the Yale Union 1891-1895.
  - TLS John Lorance to Andrew Keough re gift of papers, 1927 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Autograph letters to Mr. Lorance from:
    - Charles B. Andrews, 1892 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Simeon E. Baldwin, 1892 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Justice D.J. Brewer, 1892 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Isaac Bromley, 1892 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Justice Brown, 1892 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - M.G. Bulkeley, 1892 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Walter Camp, 1892 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Grover Cleveland, 1892 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fred W. Dallinger, 1892 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - E.S. Dana, 1892 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hon. H.L. Dawes, 1892 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Telegram from Chancey Depew (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Timothy Dwight, 1892 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - William M. Evarts, 1892 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - George P. Fisher, 1892 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - H.B. Harrison, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Samuel C. Huston, 1892 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Stephen W. Kellogg, 1892 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - T.R. Lounsbury, 1892 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Donald Grant Mitchell, 1892 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Luzon B. Morris, 1892 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - John W. Noble, 1892 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - N.G. Osborn, 1892 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - James M. Perkins, 1891 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - James M. Perkins to R.R. Upton, 1892 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - E.J. Phelps, 1892 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Charles A. Russell, 1892 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - W.E. Russell, 1892 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mr. Simonds, United States Patent Office, 1892 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Edmund Clarence Stedman, 1893 March 5, 1895 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Joseph H. Twichell, 1892 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - George L. Walker, 1892 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dean Henry P. Wright, 1892 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Typewritten manuscript entitled "The Renascence of College Debating," by John Lorance, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia
    - Constitution and By-laws of the Yale Union (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Program of the Joint Debate between the Harvard Union and the Yale Union at Sanders Theatre, 1892 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Admission ticket to the debate of January 14, 1892, 1892 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Agreement with the Hyperion Theatre management for use of the theatre, 1892 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Program of the Joint Debate at the Hyperion Theatre, 1892 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Admission ticket to the debate of March 25, 1892, 1892 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Banquet Menu, 1892 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Post card from Preston Brown to Mr. Lorance; call for drill, February 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clipping
    - Page of the New York World, January 15, 1892, with account of the first debate between the Harvard and Yale Unions at Cambridge, 1892 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)